Guide to the AFSCME, Local 420, Hospital Workers Records WAG.215
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Executive Vice-President's Files, 1980-2000.
  - Officers and Staff List (L. 420), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Organizing Conference, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Patient Abuse, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Patient Care Associates, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Patient Care Technicians, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Patient Rights, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Pay Equity/Comparable Worth, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Pensions, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Police Brutality, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Prescription Drugs, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Prisons: Food Service Contract, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Prisons: Health Care, Privatization, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Privatization, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Progressive Labor Party, Undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Public Employee Unions, New York City, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Public Employees Conference, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Public Hospitals: Sandra Obdycke Book, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Publicity (Clippings), 1981-1983 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Queens General Hospital, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Queens General Hospital: Elections and Nominations, Undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Rainbow/PUSH Coalition: Conference, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Rallies and Demonstrations, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Release Time (S.K.), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Renovation of L. 420 Offices, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - R.W.D.S.U., L. 3: Bloomingdale Workers, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Retirement/Severance: Lost Dues, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Robinson, Annette M., 1999 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Rockaway Blvd. Senior Center, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Ruiz, Alejandro (Vice-President), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Saunders, Lee, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Seaview Hospital: Neller-Gazzione Case, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Segundo Ruiz Belvis Center: Housekeeping Transfer, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Share-Care Proposal, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Shop Steward Training, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Shop Stewards: Eviction from Offices, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Shop Stewards (Lists), Undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Society of African-American Transit Employees, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - South Africa, 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Staff Meetings, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Stand Up for Children, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Supplemental Low Income for Patients (SLIP) Fund, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Tent City, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Term Limits (NYC), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Town Hall Meeting, Jun 1996 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Town Hall Meeting (Jackson, MS), 2000 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Uniform Allowance, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Union Label Dept. (AFL-CIO): Boycotts, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - United Farm Workers, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - United Negro College Fund, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - United Students Against Sweatshops, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Unity and Progress Committee (L. 420), 1995 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Vieques, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Voices of L. 420, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Welfare Reform Conference, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - Welfare Reform/Workfare, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Welfare Reform/Workfare, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - Welfare Reform/Workfare, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Welfare Reform/Workfare, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Welfare Reform/Workfare, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Welfare Reform/Workfare: Questionnaires, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Women's Committee: Candy Sale, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - Women's Conference (AFSCME), 1995 (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - Women's Conference (Western Regional), 1999 (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Women's Labor Luncheon, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Woodhull Hospital: Shop Stewards, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - Workfare: Hospital Workers Questionnaires, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 74)
- Series III: Secretary-Treasurer's Files, 1967-2002.
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Code of Ethical Practices, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Constitution, 1967, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Convention (Arrangements), 1997 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Media Oversight, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Per Capita, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Political Action News, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - AFSCME, DC 37: Secretary-Treasurer Educational Workshop, Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Benefits: General, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Benefits: Life Insurance, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Blackwell, Jacqueline, Undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Central Laundry, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Budget Cuts, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Butler, Eloise, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Butler, James; Biographical, 1976-1983 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Butler, James: Twentieth Anniversary Celebration, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Cafeterias: Privatization, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Catholic Hospitals: Mergers, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Chapman, Frieda, 1980-1984 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Chile, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Citizen Action of New York, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Citywide Contract, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Clinton, Hillary, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU), 1980-1986 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - CBTU: New York City Chapter, 1982-1987 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - CBTU: Tri-County Chapter, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), 1978-1982 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - CLUW: New York State Meeting, Buffalo, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Coney Island Hospital, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Coney Island Hospital: Layoffs, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - DeBow, Louise, Undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Delegates List, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Disbursements, Oct 1998 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Dues, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Election: Douglas Slate, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Elmhurst Hospital, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Executive Board Meeting Transcript, Mar 1999 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Gouverneur Hospital, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Grand Jury Subpoenas, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Grievance Guidelines, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Harlem Hospital Campaign, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Health and Hospitals Corporation (HHC), 1991 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - HHC: Budget Cuts, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - HHC: Cafeteria RFP's, 1995-1997 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - HHC: Institutional Services Contract, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Health Care Reform: Lamm Article, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Health Systems Agency (NYC), 1997 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Hispanic Heritage Week, L. 420: Biographies and Photos, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - IV Technicians, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Jacobi Medical Center: Training Pay, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr.: Holiday, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Labor Research Association, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Laundry Services: Privatization, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Manhattan Psychiatric Center, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - McCullen, Marshall: Photographer, Undated (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Membership: Statistics, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - Military Service Credit, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - Municipal Coalition Negotiations, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - National Labor Relations Act: Health Care Provisions, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - Office Building Renovation Project (267-9 West 124th St.), 1998 (Box 18, Folder 60)
  - Officers List, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  - Nurse Aids: One-on-One Care, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Patient Care Associates, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 63)
  - Per Diem Workers, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - Pharmacy Technicians, 1995-1997 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - Pino, Lucho: Letter on Cuba, to Bill Clinton, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 66)
  - Queens General Hospital: Urgent Injury Case, Undated (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Rallies and Demonstrations: Permits, etc., 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 68)
  - Rebate Checks, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 69)
  - Release Time, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  - Right-to-Know and Train-the-Trainer Programs, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - Salary Continuation Program, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - Salary Levels, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - Sick Leave, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - Smith, Kendreth: Biographical, Undated (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - Supplemental Low Income Patient (SLIP) Fund, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - Training and Upgrading: Grant Proposal, Undated (Box 18, Folder 77)
  - Uniform Allowance, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 78)
  - Wal-Mart, Undated (Box 18, Folder 79)
  - Webb, James, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 80)
  - Welfare Employment Program (WEP), 1997 (Box 18, Folder 81)
- Series IV: Charles v. Butler Legal Records, 1993-2009
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is closed until September 1, 2024.
  - Attorney Notes, Extra Copies of Stamped Documents, Miscellaneous, Execution of Judgment -- Attorney Notes, BJP Notes at Court Appearances, Plaintiff Interrogatories and Document Requests, Copies of Complaint, Exhibits, 2003-2004 (Box 19)
  - Local 420 - Charles v. Butler (420-48): Plaintiffs' Document Production Original Bates-Stamped Docs. 3484-4175 & 4176-4958, 1997-2002 (Box 20)
  - Audit Working Papers, Dec 31, 2000 (Box 21)
  - Local 420 AMEX & Expense/Reimbursement Reports, Balance Sheets, Audit Working Papers, Carmen Charles and L 420, Inc, v. James Butler et al. -- Motion for Default Judgment, Carmen Charles v. James Butler et al. -- Motion for Default Judgment, Local 420 Minutes of Meetings, 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Local 420-48 Charles v. Butler: Attorney Notes -- Deposition of Sarah Kennedy, Research on Motion to Compel Compliance on Subpoena Default Research, Costs and Sanctions, Execution of Judgment, Structural Volumes I, II, & III, 2003-2004 (Box 23)
  - Complaint with Exhibits, Notice of Entry, Proposed Order and Judgment, Entry of Judgments, Affidavit by Mail, Amended Notice of Settlement of Order and Judgment, Opposition to Plaintiffs' Motion for Default Judgment, New York Supreme Court, Compliance Conference, Bulletin Order, Statute of Limitations, Damages, BIP Calculations, Financial Documents, Contributions and Financial Standards, Correspondence, Order to Show Cause, Legal Correspondence, Operating Procedure -- Check Signing, Mailings, Execution of Judgment, Transcript of Judgment, Executive Judgment Research, Collections, and Accounting Issues, 2002-2004 (Box 24)
  - Peter Leon Affidavit, Henderson Deposition, Bates Stamped Documents Nos. 000420 - 000935, Plaintiffs' Document Production Original Client Docs., Plaintiff's Deposition Exhibits Aurora Santiago (Marked 1-7), 1995-2009 (Box 25)
  - Aurora Santiago's Deposition Transcripts, Copies of Plaintiff's First Set of Interrogatories and Document Requests To Defendant Sarah Kennedy; Copies of SK Responses, Bates Stamped Document Nos. 000936-001452, Pre-Litigation, Service of Process Research, 2003-2006 (Box 26)
  - Bates Stamped Document Nos. 003096-003468, Financial Documents re A. Santiago, S. Kennedy, & J. Butler, Service of Process, Research general, Bates Stamped Document Nos. 002356-003095, Plaintiffs' Document Production / Original Client Docs., 1997-2002 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence (NY SUP CT), Pre-litigation Correspondence, General Correspondence and Files, Original Deposition Transcript Taken Before Justice Karla Moskowitz, Plaintiffs' Document Production / Original Client Docs., Copies of Documents for Deposition of Enrique Campbell, Butler Transcripts, Sarah Kennedy Deposition Transcripts, Plaintiff's Deposition Exhibits / Sarah Kennedy (Marked 1-15), 1998-2004 (Box 28)
  - Copies of Plaintiff's First Set of Interrogatories and Document Requests to Defendant Aurora Santiago; Copies of A.S. Responses, and Financial Statements, 1993-2004 (Box 29)
  - Lary Cary's Working Documents (AS; SK and EC Deposition Documents), Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Financial Statements, Letter from KPMG, BJP Memos re: Butler, Answer to Kennedy and Santiago Interrogatories, Discovery & Interrogatory Reports, Answer to Interrogatories & Document Requests, Summons & Complaint (Sep 16, 2003), Affidavit of Carmen Charles in Support of Motion for Default Judgment Against Aurora Santiago Pursuant to CPLR 3215(f) (Box 30)
  - Kennedy and Santiago's Responses to Plaintiff's Discovery Requests, Original Bates Stamped Documents 005678-005683, 005684-005800, Internal Records and Expense Reimbursements, KPMG & District Attorney Investigation, Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1994 Dues Increase, Bates Stamped Documents Nos. 001453-002009, Kulikosky Deposition, 1993-2005 (Box 31)
  - Charles v. Butler: Financial Investigation, Financial Audits of DC 37 Locals, Plaintiffs' Document Production Original Bates-Stamped Docs. 4959-5677, MMS Working File, KPMG Report on Certain Financial Activities at AFSCME Local 420 and Local 420 Inc. Book 3 of 3, Draft KMPG Report, KMPG Report on Certain Financial Activities at AFSCME Local 420 and Local 420 Inc. Book, 1995-2004 (Box 32)
  - Charles v. Butler: Copies of Transcript of Meeting April 2002, Election Ballots, Original Transcript re: Official Ballot Count before Barbara Deinhardt, Report of Investigating Officer, Litigation Research, Copies of Deinhardt's Letter re Ballot Custody, Copies of Entered Hearing Exhibits, Litigation and Legal Correspondence, Bill from AAA re: 420 Officer Election, AFCSME Research Materials, Newspaper Clippings re: Charles v. Butler, Financial Investigations, Witnesses, 1999-2002 (Box 33)
  - Newspapers: The Chief 2002, Carmen Charles Litigation Hearing Exhibits, Charles v. Butler Verified Petition, Transcript of L. 420 Membership Meeting, Transcript and Manuscript (PROTEST) Local 420 Election Protest, Charles v. Butler: Newspaper Articles re: Election, Copies of Video Transcript, 2001-2003 (Box 34)
  - Local 420/DC 37: Election Materials, Election Manual, Toni Marte Hearing Exhibits (Litigation), Lee Saunders v. New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation Verified Petition, MSJ Research, Transcript and Manuscript -- Local 420 Election Protest, Affirmation in Support of Verified Petition plus Exhibits, 2001-2003 (Box 35)
  - Affidavit of Carmen Charles in Support of Order to Show Cause, Affirmation in Support of Verified Petition plus Exhibits, Local 420 Membership Meeting Minutes, Carmen Charles Campaign Materials, Verified Petitions, Orders to Show Cause, Documents re DC 1707, L 420/DC 37 Leaflets, Signed Agreement re Charles v. Butler litigation following 04/08/02 meeting, List of Names and Social Security Numbers from 03/08/02 Meeting and Petition, Resume of Georgianna Neller and Togba R. Porte, Correspondence for Geral McEntee from Carmen Charles, Transcript of Hearing (04/01/02), 2001-2002 (Box 36)
  - Local 420 Grievance Manual, Election Material, Newspapers: The Chief, Charles v. Marte & Neller Judicial Panel, Appeals from Seferian Decision (Box 37)
  - Charles v. Butler: Binders Containing, Trial Balance 12/31/01, Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Local 420 Payroll Records, 1997-2002 (Box 38)
  - Carmen Charles Election Pins, Local 420 AFSCME, AFL-CIO Balance Sheets, Legal Correspondence, Financial Statements, Legal Research, Decisions, Orders, Judgments, and Awards, Newspapers: The Chief, 2002-2003 (Box 39)
  - Carmen Charles: Affidavits Volumes 1 - 9 & Exhibits A - M, Notice of Motions, Plaintiff Statements, Memoranda of Law (Box 40)
  - Larry Cary Affidavits & Exhibit A - Q, Extra copies of Charles v. Butler Affidavits, Carmen Charles Affidavits & Exhibits A - N (N: # 1 - 9), and Peter Leons Affidavits A - C (B: # 1 - 11) (Box 41)
  - Charles v. Butler Complaint & Exhibits, Extra Copies of Affirmation in Support of Verified Petition, Copies of Entered Hearing Exhibits, Copies of Manuscript 04/01/02 Hrg. Local 420 Election Protest, Copies of Entered Hearing Exhibits, Extra Copies of Affirmation in Support of Verified Petition (03/08/02), Transcript of Local 420 Membership Meeting, C. Charles Notes, Copies of Signed Agreement re: 04/08/02 Meeting Handwritten Version & Typed Version, Attorney Notes re: Prep of Hearing Testimony, Sample Ballot for Local 420 Election, 2002-2003 (Box 42)
  - Charles v. Butler: Notice of Motion to Compel Compliance with Non-Judical Subpoena (Duces Tecum) & Exhibit Files, Affidavit in Support of Motion to Compel, Account Payable & Accrual Records, Trial Balance Sheets and Summaries, Constitution for Local 420, 1997-2004 (Box 43)
  - Hearing Transcript: Local 420 Election Protest, Transcript and Manuscript of Charles v. Butler Local 420 Election Protest, Working Files (Copies of Transcript): 3/25/01, 03/26/01, 04/01/01, & 04/08/02, 03/26/02 Transcript of Local 420 Membership Meeting, 2001-2002 (Box 44)
  - Charles v. Butler: 03/25/02 Manuscript of Local 420 Election Protest, Extra Copies of Sarah Kennedy's Marked Deposition Exhibits 1-15, WK's Notes re Prep of Hearing Testimony, Extra Copies of 10/03 Complaint Against Kennedy & Santiago, Extra Copies of Aurora Santiago's Marked Deposition Exhibits 1-7, Summary Motion Papers, Affidavits, AFSCME Preamble and International Constitution, Legal Affirmations and Court Mailings, 2001-2006 (Box 45)
  - Memorandum of Law in Support of Plaintiffs' Motion for Summary Judgment, Affidavit of Peter Leon in Support of Plaintiffs' Motion for Summary Judgment, Peter Leon Affidavit Exhibit B Volume 1 - 11, 2006 (Box 46)
  - Local 420 Report of Independent Auditors, Balance Sheet, Statement of Revenue, Expenses, Changes, and Earnings, Cash Flow and Financial Statements, Photographs, General Ledger, Liability Records, Mailings, 1994-1999 (Box 47)
  - Charles v. Butler: Memorandum of Law in Support of Plaintiffs' Motion for Summary Judgment, Affidavit of Service, Peter Leon Affidavit Exhibit B Volumes 1 - 11, Affidavit of Thomas Kulikosky in Support of Plaintiffs' Motion for Summary Judgment, Amended Notice of Motion for Summary Judgment re: Enrique Campbell, Sarah Kennedy, and Aurora Santiago, Affidavit of Larry Cary and Carmen Charles, Plaintiffs Statement of Material Facts on Motion for Summary Judgment, Amended Notices of Motions, Airborn Express and Local 295 Arbitration, 2006 (Box 48)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Emergency Executive Board Meeting Minutes, General Membership Meeting Minutes, Shop Steward Meeting Minutes, Special Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Archival Print Outs (Finding Aid), 1996-2001 (Box 49)
  - Michael Lee & Company Workpaper File Index, List of Employees, Appraisal of 267 West 124th Street, Constitution for Local 420, Financial Statements and Balance Sheets, 2000-2001 (Box 50)
  - Cost Savings/Building Expenses, A. Ward - Architecturals (i.e., ACE - Door/Hardware, ACME Steel Partitions, Admore Air Conditioning, ARC Electric, Sales Direction - Bathroom, etc.), Charles v. Butler Extra Legal Documents, Subpoenas, Affidavit of Amelia Tuminaro in Opposition to Defendant Smith's Motion to Vacate the Default Judgment, Memoranda of Law, Order to Show Cause, Opposition to Default Judgment, Plaintiffs' Reply Memorandum of Law, Motions, Attorney Notes -- Deposition of Aurora Santiago, 1999-2004 (Box 51)
  - Plaintiffs' Statement of Material Facts on Motion for Summary Judgment, Larry Cary Affidavit Exhibits A - Q, 2006 (Box 52)
  - Report to AFSCME International from AFSCME District Council 37 Local Union 420, Report on Certain Financial Activities at AFSCME Local 420 and Local 420 Inc (3 Books), 2001 (Box 53)
- Hamlet March and Rally Poster, 1992-05-02 (Flat-file-folder Shared Tamiment 112)
- "TWA Flight Attendants for Justice and Dignity in the Workforce" Poster, 1986 (Flat-file-folder Shared Tamiment 112)